Welcome to the University of Maryland Spring 2021 Commencement Ceremony.
Congratulations to the classes of 2020 and 2021.
We are emerging as fearless Terps, more thoughtful and more kind because of our experience.
We now have a new Kairos, a uniquely opportune time to decide how to move our society into a better future.
The curve of the future is yours to bend and that ultimately is why I am an optimist. Your
commitment to justice, to equity, to driving meaningful change is unlike anything that any of
us have seen before. How about a round of applause to the graduates? There has been a theme
in today's ceremony and that theme is this. From great adversity and challenge, we will rise.
Your years here have equipped you with everything you need to take on the grand challenges of our
time. You have displayed grit and confidence and perseverance and now the world needs you.
You are Terrapin Strong. Good luck and go Terps!
Please welcome the best mascot in the country,
Hestudo! Turn your castle!