My fellow Terps, I am pleased to welcome all of you to the first day of the 2021 spring
semester.
We begin this semester in extraordinary times.
We recently inaugurated Joe Biden as the 46th President of the United States, following
an election that left our nation deeply divided, and just days from a deadly assault on the
U.S. Capitol, less than 10 miles from our campus, the insurrection was also a painful
reminder of the racial inequities that remain in our country.
Last year, many members of our community lifted up their voices and took action to combat
long-standing racial injustice.
This semester, that fight must continue.
We continue to do everything we can to stop the spread of COVID-19.
Like we did in the fall, we have implemented significant health measures.
For the next 14 days, all classes will be delivered online.
And we ask all students to sequester as much as possible.
We are doubling the frequency of COVID testing for our community and are actively working
on a campus-wide vaccination distribution plan.
Even as a vaccine offers hope for the future, it is critical that we continue to wear masks,
both inside and outside, avoid large gatherings, and maintain physical distancing.
I thank all of you, especially our students, for creating a culture that holds ourselves
accountable for Maryland.
Let's keep it up.
Ensuring a strong democracy, building a more diverse, equitable, and inclusive community,
or serving the health of our friends and loved ones, these are just some of the grand
challenges of our time.
As we begin a new semester, I ask every member of our community, faculty, staff, and students
to recommit yourself to fearless grand ideas.
We all must play an active role in creating the world that we want.
Again, welcome back to the University of Maryland and congratulations on being part of our robust
and innovative academic and research community.
Together, we will pursue excellence in everything that we do.
So don't forget, wear your mask, and remain Terrapin Strong and Go Terps!